amen
amen um
all right
put a one in the chat if you are ready
to get into the word of god
this afternoon
um god is is awesome
we can say that again and god is awesome
uh we're going to jump right in today um
i want to invite you to to pray with me
as we
address the topic of the spiritual
art or the art of spiritual
bodybuilding
the art of spiritual
pray with me please heavenly father
as we spend these next few moments
together lord we pray that you would
speak to our hearts
lord that you would help me to take this
message
and lord make it applicable make it in a
way that
we will have something tangible
to leave with from this message
that we may reshape our characters lord
in jesus name we pray
amen and amen
uh
we have been
talking about this
seven week
uh character transformation training
program and this sermon today is gonna
be based around that concept uh the
appeal i'm just gonna let you know right
up front is to join that seven week
training program
um
i want to encourage you
to join that program we're going to be
having two separate groups one for men
one for women that's going to be coming
up in the chat
hopefully throughout this sermon okay
so i will be appealing to join that
through the sermon and i'll be appealing
to join it at the end of the sermon uh
all you need to do to join to become of
that part of that seven-week training
uh is to click on the link it'll be in
the chat you will see it throughout the
sermon you will see it at the end of the
sermon and you will be in the group okay
um so i want to talk to you today about
this
this spiritual this art of spiritual
bodybuilding uh we're gonna go to our
slides
and um
i want you to take a look the art
of spiritual bodybuilding uh and our
first text our first text and you may
want to take notes on this
our first text we're going to is james
chapter 1 verse 22. the bible says but
be ye doers of the word and not hearers
only deceiving your own cells
for if any man be a hearer of the word
and not a doer
he is like unto a man beholding his
natural face in a glass
for he beholdeth himself and go with his
way
and straightway forgetteth what manner
of man he was
but who so looketh into the perfect law
of liberty and continuing therein he
being not a forgetful hearer but a doer
of the work
this man shall be blessed in his deeds
so the first thing i want you to see
here is that
the word of god is likened to a mirror
the word of god or the law of god i
should say is likened to a mirror
and
having that understanding many of you
today
have looked in the mirror you've been
looking in the mirror and probably not
liking what you have seen
what you are seeing
think of this as your before
picture
right this is what motivates people to
get back into the gym this is what
motivates people to say man i gotta do
something i gotta lose the weight of sin
that's that's what we're talking about
today
but but in order to get to that place we
must first have looked in the mirror of
god's law and seen things that we think
we need to change through the power of
god matt i don't like i don't like that
i look a little angry
in the mirror
i look a little proud
in the mirror i look a little hateful
in the mirror i look a little impatient
in the mirror i don't like
the the character picture that i see
there are some things that i need to fix
about my character so put a one in the
chat if that would be you if you are one
of the people on here today who are
saying yep i have looked in the mirror
i've been looking in the mirror actually
and there are a lot of things that i see
that i don't like
put that one in the chat if that would
represent you there are things that i
see that i don't like and i would like
to change those things
in the book of hebrews chapter 12
hebrews chapter 12 and verse 1 the bible
says wherefore seeing we also are
composed about with so great a cloud of
witnesses let us lay aside every weight
and the sin that does so easily beset us
and let us run with patience the race
that is set before us so again
we are seeing here that the bible is
encouraging us to lose weight
to get rid of the weight that does so
easily
beset us
all right again i'm gonna put i'm gonna
ask you put a one in the chat
if you realize today that you need to
lose some weight
i'm talking about spiritual weight i'm
talking about the weight of sin
you have addictions you have
shortcomings you have things that you
easily fall to over and over and over
again temptations that easily blow you
over and you're saying i'm tired of this
uh i need to
drop this weight very good you're you
guys you're on the right page if you are
at the place where you realize yes i
have weight that i need to lose and and
in fact not only do you want to lose
weight but according to ephesians
chapter 6 verse 10
you realize that you also need to gain
strength
you're trying to lose weight
and gain
strength what does the bible say
ephesians chapter 6 and verse 10 it says
finally my brothers be strong in the
lord and in the power of his might
be strong in the lord and in the power
of his might so we realize that we need
to become strong
christians lord
i need strength
strengthen me i need to become stronger
than i am now so you've looked in the
mirror you said i don't like what i see
there's some things i need to there's
some weight that i need to lose and i
need to get stronger so so you're on the
right page you you're ready to make a
concentrated effort
for righteousness
and so what do we do
what should we do well philippians
chapter 2 verse 12 tells us listen to
what it tells us it tells us we need to
work out
that's what the text is telling us the
text is telling us if you want to lose
weight if you don't like what you see
you want to lose weight and you want to
become strong you need to work out look
at what the text says
wherefore my beloved as you have always
obeyed not as in my presence only but
now much more in my abstinence and what
are those next two words
put it in the chat please
what are the next two words
hmm
work out
god is calling us to work out how many
of you want to work out
what leads us to working out is
realizing ah there's some things i don't
like about myself there's some things i
don't like about my character i've
looked in the mirror i see that i'm
overweight when it comes to anger i'm
overweight when it comes to pride i'm
overweight
when it when it comes to impatience i'm
overweight when it comes to not loving
my neighbor i'm overweight in these
things and i need to lose
weight i need to lose the weight i need
to become strong in the lord and if i
want to do all this then i've got to
work out look at what the text says it
finishes off by saying
work out
your own salvation with fear and
trembling we need to work out beloved
remember this working out of our own
salvation does not mean that i take the
work out and that i work take the work
into my own hands i've got to work it
out with
jesus
i can't work it out by myself
i've got to work it out with
christ so if we're all on the same page
and right now you're saying yes pastor
i'm ready to work out i'm ready to work
out then
we need to understand some things about
working out about building muscle some
words that we're going to be looking at
today that you need to understand and
the first word that we're going to look
at is the word
catabolic
catabolic put that in the chat for me
please if you will look at the screen
what does it mean
to be in a catabolic state
type that word in the chat for me
catabolic
catabolic okay so what does it mean when
your body is in a catabolic state well
look at what the screen says it tells us
muscle wasting
is a catabolic state of the body
when the body shunts resources away from
building up your muscles and our muscles
become weaker instead of stronger
during muscle
catabolism sorry the body begins to
break down muscle protein to provide
fuel to other
functions
so
a catabolic state
is also known
as destructive metabolism
destructive metabolism you can go online
and just google destructive metabolism
and and basically what that is is a
condition in which
your body
is basically
eating muscle
your muscles are withering away
your muscles are wasting away
and the reason muscles waste away is
when they're not put to use
in other words if you're not exercising
muscle it's going to waste away if
you're not feeding the muscle if the
muscle is not recovering properly
it's going to fade away in essence you
are dying
you are dying keep that thought in mind
please i want you to notice the next
slide
so cortisol how many of you've ever
heard of cortisol
cortisol is the major catabolic steroid
of the adrenal glands
catabolic means destructive metabolism
and cortisol is made
from cholesterol so watch this
cholesterol which is fat
produces cortisol
which puts the body
in a catabolic
state
fat
puts the body in a catabolic
state now how why is cortisol
dangerous i want you to watch this i
want you to check this out cortisol is a
stretch is a stress hormone
released by
adrenal glands
it's important for helping your body
deal with stressful situations as your
brain triggers its release in response
to many different kinds of stress
however when cortisol levels are too
high for too long this hormone can hurt
you
more than it helps so watch this guys
being in a stressful situation
for too long
produces
excess levels of cortisol
which puts the body in a catabolic state
here's what i need y'all to understand
lesson number one
i need y'all to lean forward and listen
to this okay
we are naturally
in a catabolic state
put a one in the chat if you understand
what i just said
we are naturally in a catabolic
state
in other words if we do nothing the
muscles will wither away we're naturally
in a catabolic state
the question is why are we in a
naturally catabolic state why are we
dying
as someone put it before
why are we
on this
continuous process
of
death of
of uh
cannibalism well
i want you to notice with me in the book
of genesis chapter three verse seven
y'all remember the story
when adam and eve
eat from the tree of the knowledge of
good and evil and i want you to note
what happens after they eat the bible
says and the eyes of them both were open
and they knew that they were naked and
they sold fig leaves together and made
themselves apron how many of you would
say that they were stressed put a one in
the chat if you think that after they
ate from the tree they got stressed
maybe cortisol began to flood
their
system
the bible says continuing on in that
text notice what it says and they heard
the voice of the lord god walking in the
garden in the cool of the day and adam
and his wife hid themselves from the
presence of the lord god amongst the
trees of the garden were they stressful
did they have
anxiety
this was the we might say this was the
first adrenaline rush the first
spike of cortisol in mankind and it put
us listen to me it put us in a catabolic
state
naturally what am i trying to tell you
unless you do something to reverse the
catabolic state you are naturally
becoming weaker and weaker generation
after generation day after day put a one
in the chat if you understand what i'm
saying in other words
sin
breaks down
spiritual muscle
did y'all get that just now
sp sin
breaks down
spiritual
muscle
sin puts us in a natural
catabolic state
the bible says in first round chapter
three verse four whosoever committed sin
transgresses also the law for sin
is the transgression of the law
sin puts us in a naturally catabolic
state where our spiritual muscles are
continually dying
notice again with me james chapter 1
verse 14. the bible says but every man
is tempted when he is drawn away of his
own love lust and enticed
then when lust has conceived it bringeth
for sin and sin when it is finished
brings forth
death this is the protest the process of
being in a catabolic state
put a one in the chat if you've
experienced just getting weaker and
weaker spiritually
if you've ever felt like man i feel so
weak spiritually i feel so weak
spiritually beloved if we feel weak
spiritually it is because of the pr we
are in a catabolic state where our
spiritual muscles are being depleted
we're in a state of constant stress
the fat of sin is overwhelming us and we
just feel weaker and weaker paul put it
this way in romans chapter 7 verse 23
he says but i see another law in my
members
warring against the law of my mind and
bringing me into captivity
to the law of sin which is in my members
o wretched man that i am who shall
deliver me from the body of this death
paul is speaking here of the catabolic
state
this is the process of death so here's a
question what puts us in a catabolic
state
stress
poor diet
lack of rest
and inactivity
so
what is the first thing we've learned
guys we have learned
that if we do nothing
if we get up every day and don't tend to
our spiritual muscle our spiritual
strength what will happen
you will lose muscle and you will lose
strength put up put a five in the chat
if you understand what i am saying right
now if you get it if it's an aha moment
for you
your body
is never in a in a state where nothing
is happening you are either in a
catabolic state
or you're in the opposite of a catabolic
state which is the anabolic state
the anabolic state what is the anabolic
state
the anabolic state
is very simply the condition
that is necessary for your body to grow
muscle
in a catabolic state your muscles are
breaking down in an anabolic state your
muscles are building
you want to provide an atmosphere in
which your body which is conducive to
building
muscle i want to be anabolic not
catabolic put that word in the chat for
me please anabolic
anabolic now now you can begin to
understand in in a spiritual context
what 2nd peter chapter 3 verse 18 is
actually telling us look at what it says
it says here
but grow
in
grace
give me another word for that guys
be
what
anabolic
growing grace and in the knowledge of
our lord jesus christ to him be glory
both now and forevermore god is trying
to get us to grow
muscle to grow in grace to get gains yes
i like that to get gains but in order
for the body to grow in order for muscle
to grow you have to be in an anabolic
state again
psalm 92 verse 12 the righteous shall
what
shall flourish like the palm tree he
shall grow
like the cedar
like a cedar in lebanon
so
the bible is encouraging us beloved
believe it or not to be in an anabolic
state
now
i hope you're listening for the purpose
of spiritual growth you're going to get
valuable lessons if you're just trying
to grow strong physically because this
is real physical
training but i'm speak i'm speaking to
you in in a spiritual context
catabolic means the spiritual muscle is
being eaten anabolic is the condition
which is most conducive for muscles to
grow
are y'all with me so far
i want you to notice how romans 6 then
points out the transformation
from
catabolic to anabolic listen to what the
bible says romans 6 verse 16 the bible
says know ye not that to whom you yield
yourself servants to obey his servants
you are to whom you obey
whether of sin unto death
catabolic
or of obedience unto righteousness
anabolic
being then made free from sin
catabolic you became the servants of
righteousness
anabolic
verse 19 i speak after the manner of men
because of the because of the infirmity
of your flesh for as you have yielded
your members servants to uncleanness and
to iniquity unto iniquity catabolic even
so now yield your members servants to
righteousness and holiness anabolic are
y'all with me
for when you were servants of sin
catabolic you were free from
righteousness what fruit had ye then in
those things where you have nourished
where you are now ashamed for the end of
those things is death catabolism your
body is eating itself the muscles are
withering away you have no strength
but
not being made free from sin i'm no
longer in the catabolic state
and become servants of unto god i'm not
in the anabolic state you have your
fruit unto holiness and the end is
everlasting life why watch this for the
wages of sin
is catabolic but the gift of god is
anabolic
the ways of sin is death but the gift of
god is eternal life
through jesus christ
our lord so beloved what i'm trying to
tell you is that we need to put the body
in a state in which it is most conducive
to growth
are you all with me
is this making sense
what
pastor what kind of environment can i
put my body in to to to maximize growth
that i know that's what you're asking
now how can i make my body more anabolic
well i want you to notice galatians
chapter 5 and verse 16. notice the text
you guys this i say then watch
walk
in
the spirit
and you shall not fulfill the lust of
the flesh
for the lust for the flesh lusteth
against the spirit and the spirit
against the flesh and these are contrary
one to the other so that you cannot do
the things that you would so watch this
guys
if you want
to grow
you got to put yourself in the spirit
you have to walk
in the spirit
why because it is the most conducive
atmosphere
for anabolic growth to occur so watch
this
bodybuilders right weight lifters will
take what are called anabolic steroids
those are illegal
anabolic steroids are basically what
makes people get these huge muscles i
mean
huge must make me look small make me
look tiny
they they are putting putting their body
in a certain condition where the
anabolic power just explodes
now we want that without using drugs
we want that but we want it legally and
god says you can get that by putting
yourself in the spirit by walking in the
spirit when you walk in the spirit
you're putting your body in the in the
prime atmosphere
for
explosive
spiritual
muscle growth put a seven in the chat if
you want to blow up
put a seven in the chat if you would
like to walk around spiritually like
this
put a 7 in the chat if you want some
tremendous
spiritual biceps and triceps
and shoulders and legs to hold you up
if you're walking in the spirit you're
in an anabolic condition if you're
walking in the flesh you're in a
catabolic
condition so our goal
is to try to keep ourselves in an
anabolic state now
being in an anabolic state you can't
just be like hey i'm in an anabolic
anabolic state and now my muscles gonna
grow no
there are several things that must
happen for you to grow your muscle it's
not just about being anabolic you
actually have to exercise listen
carefully three things that are
necessary you gotta exercise you gotta
look at your diet and you have to rest
put those three things in the chat for
me exercise
diet
and rest
now let's break these down one by one
how y'all doing so far by the way
are you learning some valuable things
put a seven in the chat if you never
knew before
the difference between catabolic state
and anabolic state i didn't know that
wow i didn't know and if i am not if if
i'm not exercising
a daily my muscle is naturally going to
wither away it's the same thing if i'm
not spiritually building muscle i'm
either anabolic or catabolic i'm never
in between
so the body is either leaning catabolic
or leaning anabolic we always want to be
leaning anabolic because if we're not
leaning anabolic we are naturally
getting weaker
naturally becoming less and less
powerful
naturally losing spiritual muscle
alright so
exercise
diet and rest let's talk about exercise
and now in exercise i need to introduce
you to three more
words three more words i want you to
notice the screen remember anabolic
means you're building spiritual muscle
fat about
catabolic
catabolic it means the fat of sin is
taking over your spiritual body
yeah
all right all right let's move let's
move
in exercise there are three
phases to every movement
so i first want to talk to you about the
concentric
phase what is the concentric phase the
concentric phase is the lifting phase
it is the phase of movement whereby the
load you are the weight is resisting
gravity
in the concentric phase the load is
always moving towards the clouds
an easy way to remember this is c
equals concentric and c
equals
clouds
yeah i just should use that word
fatabolic y'all
may as well use it right talking about
the fat of sin that's a condition we're
in but no let me let me come back here
i'm gonna explain this to you
so the concentric phase if you're
working out right and you got the weight
in your hand
when you are lifting when you are
curling your muscles
that's the concentric phase right you're
going towards the heavens the clouds
concentric
is anytime you're contracting
the muscle
always think of this if you're squatting
concentric is when you're on the up
motion if you're doing overhead press
concentric is when you're right
constant concentric you're always
moving towards the heavens
now
think of it in this way to build muscle
you need several movements one of them
is concentric but i'm going to share
something with you about that in a
little while okay those of you who are
in the
seven week transformation uh launch last
week you know what i'm about to say but
i'm gonna add some things that i did not
share with you in that uh in that
opening presentation okay uh and for
those of you who aren't there you're
getting the whole thing right now you're
getting more right now than what we did
last week okay
so
concentric i want you to think of it
this way there is concentric
righteousness
concentric is when you're putting
positive force
to do something right your your think of
it like this
you are
going out of your way to do good think
of that as concentric righteousness
right concentric righteousness is
lifting others up to heaven think of it
like that
concentric righteousness is when we go
about
doing
good
doing good to others when you're helping
that lady cross the street that old lady
across the street or the old man across
the street that is concentric
righteousness right that's the
contraction that's where you're you're
putting forth uh effort to do something
watch now watch i'm going somewhere with
this
um you're lifting other people up to
heaven so notice with me galatians
chapter 6 verse 10 for example the bible
says here as we have therefore
opportunity
let us do good
unto all men
especially unto them who are of the
household of faith so like the good
samaritan very good that is concentric
righteousness doing good to others that
is concentric righteousness isaiah 58
verse 6 is not this the fast that i've
chosen to lose the bands of wickedness
to undo the heavy burdens and to let the
oppressed go free and that you break
every yoke isn't that to deal thy bread
to the hungry and that thou bring the
poor that are cast out to thy house when
you see the naked that you cover him and
that you hide not yourself from your own
flesh this is
concentric righteousness you're lifting
other people up up to the clouds up to
heaven right you're showing them a
picture of god through your good deeds
through your good actions so so this is
concentric
it is important is it important for us
to exercise concentric righteousness yes
or no
to lift others to heaven to to put
efforts forth to do good
and to
you know to help other people
however
concentric righteousness
let me say this way the concentric phase
of a workout is not what builds your
muscle
let me say it again
the concentric phase of the workout is
not where the most stress is on the
muscle in order for muscle to grow it
must first be torn
it must be stretched
and that beloved is what we call
the
eccentric
phase the eccentric phase notice what
the text notice the the term
eccentric
what is eccentric
let me see
let me come back here
so is the eccentric motion is where you
are s lengthening the muscle
so eccentric is on the way
down
are you with me
uh eccentric is on the way down i'm
gonna uh get to a slide here just give
me one here we go i want you to know
what it says no no no no that's not the
slide that's not the slide
i almost gave that away right there
okay yeah i didn't even put this slide
in here i don't know how it escaped but
let me just tell you what what this same
article from which i got the think of c
as in going towards the clouds
eccentric is where you're lengthening
the muscle you're stretching the muscle
and the eccentric motion is always going
down towards the earth so the article
says think of this as if c stands for
clouds then the eccentric phase would be
equal to earth now you're moving down so
anytime you're moving down to the earth
in the motion anytime you're going
towards the ground that is eccentric
this is where the muscle stretches this
is where the muscle tears this is where
this is where the muscle tears when
you're going when you're in a you're
doing a squat when you are going down
this is where the major
muscle strengthening happens
and it's it's really interesting because
if you if you've ever been in the gym
you will see people doing this all the
time and i used to do
like the all the weight is this and then
they let it drop
not realizing that this is not what
builds the muscle
it's the slow resistance
when you're holding that weight and
letting it descend slowly and the muscle
is being torn as it's going down towards
the earth this is what builds the muscle
and therefore when you're exercising
this is the phase that you want to slow
down concentric
eccentric
that's where the muscle is torn
i need you to understand this beloved
this is where the muscle goes through
trial
[Music]
this is where we learn beloved to
to to to to
to go towards the ground to die to self
watch watch what the text says james 4 6
the bible says god gives more grace
wherefore he saved god resisted the
pride but giveth grace unto the humble
submit yourself therefore the god resist
the devil
and he will flee from you
resist this is where resistance happens
resist the devil and he will flee from
you
this is this is crazy guys listen to
this
we might be strong we might have
concentric strength oh i can go out and
feed the homeless oh i can do something
nice for my neighbor i can do something
good for my brother or my sister or a
friend or a stranger but beloved when it
comes to eccentric motion somebody said
something to you that you don't like all
of a sudden it's not uh it's
we have no eccentric strength
we have no strength to lower ourselves
to humble ourselves to resist
the devil to resist temptation and so
while we might be very strong
concentrically oh look look look look
when it comes to eccentric power we have
none
we can't resist getting angry we can't
resist uh uh getting impatient we can't
resist these things why because we don't
want trial and trial beloved is what
strengthens
the muscle
trial beloved is what see it's one thing
to to be nice to your neighbor that's
great
and overall it helps to strengthen you
but if you don't have no trial
if you don't have any trial in your life
and soft we're like i don't want any
trial if you don't want any trial you
can't get stronger
you cannot get stronger if you don't
have any trial we must learn to
strengthen and lengthen
the muscle stretch the muscle
that's why beloved if you're doing a
bench press listen to me if you're doing
a bench press it's not this motion
that is going to grow your chest it's
when you're coming down and now you feel
the stretch and the tearing
and and bodybuilders say you need to go
feel that stretch so now it's like ah
you feel the muscle
tearing
this is what grows the chest beloved
it's that stretch
we don't like the stretch
we don't like the tear
but beloved it is necessary if we want
to become stronger by the way how many
of you would like to join the seven week
training program
there's 500 and some odd of you watching
right now
there should be 500 ones in this chat
right now there should be
there should be unless you can't type
for whatever reason there should be
but beloved listen to me
let's put it in the chat i don't know if
uh who let's if we can get the link in
the chat people who are saying i already
want to sign up for this seven-week
training program
let's put that link in the chat i need
y'all to sign up but keep please follow
me
please follow me
if the muscle is not lengthened it's not
going to grow
if we're not willing to be stretched
we're not going to grow
that is the bottom line so while it
might be easy to feed your neighbor or
to be good to those that are good to you
when the bible says i say unto but i say
unto you love your enemies do good to
them which hate you bless them that
curse you and pray for them that
despitefully use you now we're talking
about muscle stretching
now we're talking about muscle
stretching see
it's not a stretch
for me to be kind
to my family to my brothers and sisters
uh to my wife to to my that's not a
stretch
but it is a stretch for me to be kind to
someone that i know does not like me
someone that i know
does not have the best in mind for me
now you're stretching
and that's where character grows that's
where the muscle grows beloved
we must be
willing
to be stretched
for god
i want you to check out these statements
from manuscript volume 8 1899
the the the heading is stretch every
nerve and i want you to notice this
we must put to the stretch
every spiritual nerve and muscle
god does not desire you to remain
novices he wants you to reach the very
highest round of the ladder and then
step from it into the kingdom of our
lord and savior jesus christ let me read
another one uh um
amazing from the from the the
um devotional amazing grace we may make
daily progress in the upward path to
holiness and yet we find still greater
heights to be reached but every stretch
of the spiritual muscle every taxation
of heart and brain brings to light the
abundance of the supply of grace
essential for us as we advance how about
this one
here are man's works and here are god's
works with these two combined man will
be victorious and receive a crown of
life at last he must put to the stretch
every spiritual nerve and muscle that he
may be a successful overcomer in this
work and that he may obtain the precious
boon of eternal life in other words if
we want to be fit for the kingdom we got
we have to stretch
the muscle
there are many who are simply
passive church members they do not feel
the necessity for of struggling for
immortality but god calls upon all to
throw their energies into the warfare to
put the stretch to put to the stretch
every muscle and exert every power in
order to be found worthy of eternal life
half-hearted and england's service will
not be accepted acceptable to god the
servant of god must gain
increased ability by using what he has
reviewing herald june 19th i need y'all
to understand this i need you to see
this okay
stretch of muscle what is the author
talking about there
the author is talking about
eccentric
motion
because a muscle will not grow you when
you're contracting the muscle it's not
breaking down
in order for the muscle to go it must be
stretched
and that's why people often do exercises
wrong they're not focused on the stretch
they're focused on the contracting we
need to learn how to focus on the
stretch to get the most out of our
spiritual workout are y'all with me so
far put a one in the chat if you're
understanding now i need to we we've
talked about concentric we've talked
about eccentric now i want you to notice
something regarding the eccentric motion
because there's another word we need to
learn here another phrase and it is
progressive
overload put that in a chat for me
please progressive overload man
yes yes yes
progressive overload what is that
you might be asking right now
what is progressive overload
progressive overload is where you are
continually
overloading the muscle so in other words
if on your first set right you're doing
five repetitions of
uh 25 pounds
progressive overload says on your next
set you want to do 5 reps of 30 pounds
you're progressively overloading the
muscle here's why
if you don't increase the weight
you are not going to get stronger
you're not going to grow muscle
so if you've been lifting weight for
years and you are benching 125 and 10
years later you're still benching 125
something is wrong
and if you're not focused on intentional
progressive overload your muscle is not
going to grow you're not going to get
stronger this is why the bible tells us
in first peter chapter 4 verse 12 listen
what it says beloved think it not
strange concerning the fiery trial which
is to try you as though some strange
thing happened unto you but rejoice
inasmuch as you are partakers of
christ's suffering that when his glory
shall be revealed you may be glad also
with exceeding
joy
do y'all understand this
the reason why
god will allow trials to come upon you
is because he's trying to get you
progressively stronger think of the life
of job progressive overload
and beloved some it doesn't have to be
that dramatic but i need you to
understand if god's trying to grow you
which he is
he's not just going to keep bringing the
same 10 pound trial to you
many of us just want 10 pound trial
10 pound trial
we can just throw it around
and then walk around like i'm strong
beloved listen to me
the reason why god sends
the
the the
the crazy maniac
the reason why god allows the crazy
situation is because
progress of progressive overload he
doesn't want you to plateau to maintain
and beloved you got to understand that
if i'm not willing
if i want to stay at the same place that
i am
eventually
the catabolic state is going to kick in
because if your muscles not growing it's
shrinking
did y'all catch what i just said
if you're not growing you're shrinking
there's no this
if you're not growing you are shrinking
and by the way
yeah
you can actually look muscular and be
weak
wow
there is a way in which you can train
where you look muscular but you're
weak we don't want to just
look like spiritually strong christian
christians we want to actually be
spiritually strong christians so now i
want to introduce to you one one more
phrase in the exercise context and then
we're going to get to diet no no hold on
i got some other things i need to share
with you watch watch watch watch
the isometric phase
so what is isometric mean what does
isometric mean
the isometric phase of the movement
watch this let me come back to the
camera here the isometric phase of the
movement is where you're simply holding
the weight you're not
contracting it's not
concentric
it's not eccentric you stopped right
here and you're just holding the weight
so sometimes you'll see trainers go when
you're exercising explode up concentric
come slowly down
eccentric feel the stretch and now hold
tension
endurance test your endurance you're
holding it that's the that's the
isometric phase of the movement and the
isometric phase of the movement is
designed to strengthen your endurance
your holding power
your holding power your under pressure
power
are y'all feeling this are y'all
catching what i'm saying
notice the texture on matthew 24 verse
12 why is it important to train
isometrically listen matthew 24 12 the
bible says and because iniquity shall
abound the love of many shall wax coal
but he that shall endure
unto the end the same shall be saved
beloved we have to learn how to endure
how about this one mark mark 16 the
parable of the sower in the seed and
these are they likewise which are sown
in stony ground who have when they heard
the word immediately receded with
gladness and have no root in themselves
and so they endure for a time
but afterward when affliction or
persecution arises for the word sake
immediately they are offended
no endurance power
how about this hebrews chapter 12 verse
6 for whom the lord loveth he chasteneth
and escorts with every son whom he whom
he receives if you endure chastening
god deals with you as sons for what son
is he whom the father does not chasten
and this one james 1 12 blessed is a man
that endureth temptation
for when he is tried
he shall receive the crown of life which
the lord has promised to them that love
him and watch one more on this here is
the patience of the saints here are they
that keep the commandments of god
beloved it is learning how to endure so
watch this
concentric positive righteousness it is
lifting others up to heaven it is
necessary but listen that's not where
the real strength training occurs it's
on the eccentric motion where your
muscle is being stretched where you're
resisting
where where you're going down to the
earth you're humbling yourself this is
where the power is and then of course
that that that isometric phase where
you're learning to endure
you're learning to endure so how can i
how can i do this training pastor there
is one exercise you need to do
one exercise you need to do and the
bible talks about that exercise it's
found in matthew 16 verse 24 and beloved
it is what we will call
cross-training cross-training
pastor what is cross-training jesus said
it
then jesus said unto his disciples if
any man will come after me let him deny
himself and take up his cross and follow
me for whosoever will save his life
shall lose it and whosoever will lose
his life for my sake shall find it
cross training pick up the cross
pick up the cross pastor how is picking
up the cross how does picking up the
cross include
concentric motion
eccentric motion and
metric how does that work well let me
show you
you see if we look at isaiah 53 and
verse 3 the bible said
says here he is despised and rejected of
men a man of sorrows and acquainted with
our grief and we hid as it were our
faces from him he was despised and we
esteemed him not surely he has borne our
grief and carried our sorrows yet we did
esteem him stricken smitten of god and
afflicted but he was wounded for our
transgressions he was bruised for our
iniquities the chastisement of our peace
was upon him and with his stripes we are
healed i need you to understand
something here
when christ picked up his cross
and went to calvary do you want to know
what he was doing
he was doing a concentric motion
he was lifting us
up
to the heavens
he died
to give us access to heavenly places
he was lifting others up
in that act
that was the concentric motion
in fact let me read this to you
what a theme the author says what a
theme from meditation is the sacrifice
that jesus made
for
lost sinners see that concentric motion
for lost sinners he does it on behalf of
others he was wounded for our
transgressions he was bruised for our
iniquities the chastisement of our peace
was upon him and with his stripes we are
healed how shall we estimate the
blessings thus brought within our reach
could jesus have suffered more could he
have purchased for us richer blessings
should it not melt the hardest heart
that
when we remember that for our sakes
he left the happiness and glories of
heaven and suffered poverty and shame
cruel affiction and a terrible death
hiding not by his death and resurrection
opened for us the door of hope we should
have known nothing but the horrors of
darkness and the miseries of despair in
our present state favored and blessed as
we are we cannot realize from what
depths we have been rescued we cannot
measure how much deeper our afflictions
would have been how much greater our
woes had not jesus encircled us with his
human arm of sympathy and love and
lifted us
up
testimonies volume 5 page 316 christ
lifted us up when he took up the cross
concentric motion do you see it
beloved not only did he not only did he
exercise a concentric motion in bearing
the cross he also exercised an eccentric
motion pastor what are you saying i want
you to watch with me
according to matthew 27 verse 40
the bible says here thou that destroyeth
the temple that's what they were saying
to jesus and build it in three days save
thyself if thou be the son of god come
down from the cross likewise also the
chief priests mocking him with the
scribes and elders said he saved others
himself he cannot save if he be the king
of israel let him come down from the
cross and we will believe him i need you
to understand
that jesus
jesus
in that act of being on the cross for us
in that act of resisting the wicked
suggestions of the devil
in that act beloved jesus was doing an
eccentric motion he was resisting the
devil he was resisting evil beloved he
was resisting coming down from the cross
by
dying to self
jesus on the cross beloved not only
exercised a concentric motion by lifting
others up but exercise eccentric power
by resisting the devil and not only this
beloved but there was a progressive
overload put a seven in the chat y'all
if you feel me right now
there was progressive overload in this
final trial of jesus
pastor what are you talking about let's
go to the screen what do you mean
progressive overload listen to what the
text says matthew 26 37 and he took with
him peter and the two sons of zebedee
and began to be very sorrowful and very
what
come on y'all very what
very heavy the weight upon his shoulders
was very heavy in the garden then he
said unto unto them my soul is exceeding
sorrowful even unto death tarry you you
hear and watch with me beloved
this
was a heavy burden
it was heavy see him in the garden of
gethsemane as he's praying
father if it be possible
let this cup pass from me the cup was
heavy and getting heavier by the moment
progressive overload so first my soul is
heavy heavy it's it's it's sorrowful
unto death and then he's in the garden
and he's praying and this agonizing
prayer it's getting heavier but it
doesn't stop there beloved because god
threw on more weight
matthew 26 47 and while he hits fake
lord judas one of the twelve one of his
own one of his boys
came and with him a great multitude with
swords and stabs from the chief priests
and the elders of the people now he that
betrayed him gave him a sign saying
whomsoever i shall kiss that same is he
hold him fast i need you to understand
this beloved this is progressive
overload for jesus okay okay i'm gonna
give myself up but now it's one of my
own that's betrayed me
at every moment it's like god is putting
on greater weight
on the shoulders
of jesus christ
the progressive overload doesn't stop
there because in matthew 26 verse 56 it
says all this was done that the
scriptures of the prophets might be
fulfilled then
all the disciples
forsook him and fled
progressive
overload
not only
do i feel this heavy pressure not only
have i prayed lord let this cup father
let this cup pass from me but one of my
own betrays me and now all 12 have
forsaken me progressive overload and it
doesn't stop there because the bible
tells us in matthew 26 and verse 64
jesus says unto them thou has said
nevertheless i say unto you hereafter
you shall see the son of man sitting on
the right hand of power and coming in
the clouds of heaven then the priest
rent his clothes saying he has spoken
blasphemy what further need have we of
witnesses behold you have heard his
blasphemy
what think he they answered he is guilty
of death then did they spit in his face
and buffeted him another smote him with
the palms of their hand i'm talking
beloved about progressive overload
how strong are you jesus
and yes
i love that courtney he didn't have a
spotter
there was no one there just in case he
was about to drop the weight so imagine
jesus beloved and he is benching the
weight of the whole world and if you
thought that was heavy now i want you to
put this on top of it now i want you to
put on top of it that all your disciples
have forsaken you now put on top of it
that you're supposed to die and they
spit on you and they accuse you of
blasphemy
can it get heavier
how about this
now peter sat without the palace in the
it sat without in the palace and a
damsel kingdom came unto him saying thou
also was with jesus of galilee but he
denied before them all saying i know not
what you say now listen y'all it's one
thing to be like
oh we ran because we were nervous
but now the very man that was like jesus
listen if everybody else forsakes you
i'm your boy
he doesn't just say
well i wasn't with him i know but
i don't know him
i don't know him oh
yes y'all yes
the lamb is the goat
i love it
jesus christ is the goat
i just need to preach a sermon call that
the goat
he is the greatest of
all time
he is the strongest of all time
you think the progressive overlord would
stop there beloved listen
matthew 27 verse 46 and about the ninth
hour jesus cried out with a loud voice
saying eli eli lemaster back tonight
they just say my god my god why hast
thou
forsaken me
this beloved is the greatest load and
this is what bro this is what took the
very life of jesus
do y'all understand this
progressive overload builds muscle and
it i'm telling you it's
what about the isometric phase
what about the isometric phase i want
you to check this out hebrews 12 2
looking onto jesus the author and finish
of our faith who for the joy that was
set before him endured the cross
pause
remember how i said in the isometric
phase you're neither all the way up in
heaven you're neither all the way to the
earth you're in the middle and you're
just holding it there
beloved jesus
was suspended
between heaven
and earth
and in that isometric stage
he was held there on the cross
how long can he hold this
how long can he hold his position will
he come down
will he say i've had enough
beloved i need you to understand that
jesus demonstrated what it means to be a
strong believer to be a strong christian
he was not only strong concentrically he
was not only strong eccentrically but
for hours he stayed there holding his
position with no spotter
is he gonna lose his anger is he gonna
lose
is he gonna is he gonna get mad is he
gonna curse him what's he gonna do and
jesus is there just like this
listen guys
if you don't know how to train you're
not gonna get strong that's the bottom
line and many of us as christians
we don't know how to we're not even
training we're just like man i got beat
up today
and then we go on about our business
listen we got to talk about diet
we're almost there guys we're almost
done we got to talk about diet
so i need you to understand that in diet
and diet let's go to the screen
so
with diet uh
two things are important
for muscle building
i want to focus on protein i don't want
to focus on timing
so i need you to understand
that the word of
god is the protein for the muscle put a
one in the chat if you understand what i
just said
the word of god is protein to spiritual
muscle
you you catch this let me show you
let me show you uh first peter 2 2 as
newborn babes
desire
[Music]
desire the sincere milk of the word that
you may grow thereby
see
adding the word to your diet
causes them so once the muscle's broken
down then you add your protein and
because the body has a lot of protein in
it the the muscle is gonna grow listen
to me uh if you're lifting weights and
you're not getting uh enough protein to
to
be involved in the process of healing
the muscle your muscles not gonna grow
you're not going to get stronger so
think of the word of god as your protein
powder
listen to what the bible says
listen again
uh psalms 103 verse 20 bless the lord ye
his angels that excel in strength that
do his commandments hearkening unto the
voice of his word so if the angels who
are super strong get strong by
hearkening to the word of god then we
too must understand that we have to
we should be eating that protein
now i need you to understand if you're
eating protein but you're not exercising
concentric eccentric isometric if you're
not exercising the protein goes to waste
that's why so many of us read the word
of god but because we're not working out
and because we're not intentional about
trial intentional about overcoming ah
here's an opportunity for me to get
stronger let me see if i can bench this
yo yo what are you doing man you can't
bench that no no no let me try see you
have to be bold as a bodybuilder you got
to look that way and say i know i can
bench that i can bench that in christ i
can bench that in christ jesus
you have to have that kind of confidence
if you're scared about the weight i
don't know your mind will short circuit
and you'll be like i can't do this and
you're not even going to try but if you
see that when you're like all right yeah
i can do this i got this
listen psalm 119 verse 11 thy word have
i hid in my heart that i might not sin
against thee if you have protein in the
body
it's going to prevent you from going
into a catabolic state but the protein
must be coupled with exercise right with
concentric eccentric isocentric uh
isometric you have to exercise along
with the protein that's why the bible
says man shall not live by bread alone
but by every word that proceedeth out of
the mouth of god this is your protein
everyone
now i need you to listen carefully to me
because bodybuilders understand listen
to me now
listen to me now
bodybuilders understand that one of the
ways you keep the body in an anabolic
state is that you have to eat often you
ever seen bodybuilders and they'll eat
like every four hours like these small
meals every four hours the reason they
do that is because they're trying to
keep the body anabolic that means the
muscle's always growing even at night
they they are sleepaholics but at night
they will get up in the middle of the
night and and get a protein shake
so that the body is consistently in an
anabolic state
beloved listen to me we are talking
about spiritual workouts here and if
that is true then we need to be eating
the word of god every few hours
not just one time during the day but we
need to be consistently eating these
these meals
hours apart let me get some more bread
let me get some more bread i'm gonna
grab some more bread here you're always
eating
to keep the body in an anabolic state
what does this do number one
it allows you to have energy for the
workout
if you don't have enough energy for the
workout you're not going to be able to
last through the workout and beloved
you don't know what trial is coming at
you today
did you eat today
no i just grabbed the bite
you just grabbed the bite so how are you
going to manage the workout that god is
saying that i have planned for you today
because i had a workout plan for you
today i thought we were trying to
oh boy i don't mean to direct your
attention here but
we need to stop eating junk food
there there's a bodybuilder and he he
you know he's he's famous he does he
does these little
skits of whenever you know someone is
training is eating and he'll walk up to
them and just slap the food out their
hand what are you doing you're not
supposed to be eating that
don't worry about who that is anyway the
point is
we are often eating the stuff that we
shouldn't and the stuff that we should
be eating we don't eat
not only should we be eating before
every workout to get the most out of our
exercise but after the workout that
post-nutrition that post-workout
nutrition is crucial we got to eat right
after the workout beloved when you're
tempted and you make it through eat
right after the workout
eating every few hours prevents
cannibalism from setting in
and by the way i'm gonna say something
else right now and we're almost there
beloved we're almost there we're almost
there
you need to eat meat
what somebody's going to take this video
clip it
cut it off someone who doesn't like me
they're going to cut it off and say
watch where pastor meyer said you need
to eat meat
yes y'all
if you want to get strong
you need
to eat
meat
pastor what are you saying hold on hold
on you come on y'all you know it's not
what you think
you know it's not what you think
hebrews 5 12 for the time for when for
the time you ought to be teachers you
have need that one teach you again which
be the first principles of the article
of god and are become such as have need
of milk not strong meat for everyone
that uses milk is unskillful in the word
of righteousness for he is a babe
but strong meat belongs to them that are
of full age even those who by reason of
use have their senses exercised to
discern both good and evil let me say it
again if you want to get strong you need
to eat meat the meat of the word of god
amen
eat meet y'all
spiritual meet y'all
that is what is going to get you strong
now
i cannot go further without telling you
stay hydrated
stay hydrated note note this y'all we're
almost done i promise you we're almost
done i want you to know this stay
hydrated that is another thing that is
designed to help the muscles grow you
have to stay hydrated notice
that not drinking from another article
on working out that not drinking enough
water hurts performance on multiple rep
multiple set resistance exercises isn't
surprising
researchers believe that even mild
dehydration
reduces central drive in other words
your brain
tells you to stop
your brain tells you to stop another
study came to a similar conclusion
improper hydration reduces performance
on multiple rep resistance exercises and
also makes the exercise feel harder
so a strength workout will likely feel
more unpleasant when you don't drink
enough water before
hand
stay
hydrated y'all
stay hydrated if you are not drinking in
if you are not drinking enough water the
trial looks more difficult
if you're not drinking enough water the
temptation seems more unbearable
mind that the brain is going to tell you
nah you can't overcome that
do you understand what i'm saying stay
hydrated all the time stay hydrated
jesus answered and said unto the woman
whosoever drinketh of this water shall
thirst again but whosoever drinketh of
the water that i shall give him shall
never thirst the water that i shall give
him shall be in him a well of water
springing up into eternal life beloved
we've got to drink the water of the word
stay hydrated stay replenished
stay in the holy spirit y'all
you're not just gonna build muscle
you're not just gonna build i'll give
you my notes you y'all get my sermon
notes for those of you that want it but
again
all of this beloved is setting you up
for this seven week training program you
can do it privately on your own you
could do it with the group of men you
can do with a group of women put there
it is in the chat i want to be a part of
i want to intentionally
muscle uh train for strength tr now
watch this watch this
if you don't stay hydrated that means
bringing in the spirit of god and
keeping yourself and your mind in a
place where where where the holy spirit
is just saturating your cells and your
mind and your thoughts
you're going to see temptation as more
difficult oh this is so hard oh
trust me
water
i read somewhere that that when your
muscles are filled with water you it can
make you up to 30 percent if either 30
i think it's 30 percent stronger than
you would be without water and that's
why you see bodybuilders always drinking
water
because the muscle is made up mostly of
water so if you don't have any water in
the muscle your strength is depleted
stay
hydrated y'all
so we got to talk about this last thing
all right
we need to talk about burning fat
we need to talk about brain we've been
talking about building muscle we just
now need to talk about burning fat and
then we're done
what is the best way to burn fat
what is the best way to burn fat how do
we burn
fat
and the answer beloved oh i like that
andre spiritual creatine
i don't know if you know it but creatine
draws water into the muscle
creatine draws water into the muscle
when you that think of the of the word
of god as that spiritual creatine you
got to take it every day because it's
going to draw water into the muscle and
keep you hydrated no
good
so do me a favor please if
if you were
if you know of anyone that was watching
send them the link let them know because
i don't know what just happened
like seriously
i don't think any of us touched anything
and uh
this thing just ended
so
are you all good
i'm just gonna wait we had over almost
600 people on and
all right we're just gonna wait just a
minute we're gonna wait just a minute if
you can please help me out by just
sharing the link again letting other
people know
that
we're continuing on okay
um so let me do this um
they'll catch on they'll they'll
hopefully they'll get in here
um where was i at
where was i at okay
so
heavenly father
um we just thank you for giving us this
opportunity lord to
finish this sermon
lord um whatever happened just now i
pray that everyone that was watching
before that was getting on an
understanding
that they will be able to tune in
uh to this uh link lord
and that your spirit will continue to
flow the way that it has been in jesus
name we pray amen and amen
all right
um
we're talking about burning fat
and um
how do we burn
fat how do we burn fat let us go back to
the screen
and i want you to see this and i want
you to take it in very carefully okay
the way that we burn fat
one of the most efficient ways of
burning fat
is by walking
it's by
walking
walking might not be the most strenuous
form of exercise but it is an efficient
way to get in shape and burn fat
while we can't spot reduce that means
focus on one area
right and lose weight there while we
can't spot reduce fat
walking can help reduce overall fat
including belly fat
which
despite being one of the most dangerous
types of fat
it is also one of the easiest to lose
so i want you to understand that one of
the ways one of the most effective ways
to lose fat
is to walk
it is to walk
put that in the chat guys
walk
how does that relate to our spiritual
exercise
2 corinthians chapter 5 17 describes
what i like to call faith walking
for we walk
by
faith
not by
sight
we must learn
how to
walk by faith and what does that mean
what does walking by faith mean what is
faith the bible says in hebrews 11 verse
1 now faith is being sure of what we
hope for and certain of what we do not
see so let me break this down for you
i want you to imagine faith walking like
this faith walking requires me to use
faith we use faith not sight so pastor
what are you saying
what i'm saying is
faith walking means you're walking
towards a goal
you have to see yourself by faith
for who you want to be
seven weeks from now
seven months from now
seven years from now
see that which is not reality as if it
were reality
are you with me
so so so you got to get your steps in
yes because as you're learning to walk
by faith that means
when you see yourself in the future man
in the future i am super patient in the
future i am i am super kind in the
future i i i bear temptation powerfully
in the future i don't get irritated so
that's your faith walk so by faith you
imagine the person that you want to be
in christ and now you're walking
according to that picture
go out there today and walk today as if
you already have spiritual muscle walk
today as if you're already patient walk
today as if you're already
long-suffering walk it live it by faith
get your faith walk in every day and
what happens is that the more you walk
in faith is the more sin is burned
is the more fat you lose
because you're walking in faith you're
walking a comp you're walking in the
picture that you you want people seven
weeks from now seven months from now
seven years from now to be like man what
have you been doing you look different
what should i doing you look like jesus
how did that happen
what dream are you going to
you walk in the picture that you have
i've seen for yourself this is what i
want to be in christ
this is who i want to be in christ you
need to see your before
your after picture
you need to see your after picture
what do i want to be
who do i want to be
what do i want people to say about me
when they think about my christian
character
so listen
listen
not only can you walk you can also run
yeah
you can also run we're foreseen we are
all accomplished about what's so great a
cloud of witnesses let us lay aside
every weight and the sin which does so
easily beset us and let us run with
patience the race that is set before us
you can run
you see sometimes when we first begin
when we first begin it's kind of like um
we
we uh
let me say it this way
all we can do is walk
but as we learn to walk and and we get
better at walking then we become
we become
we cannot start to run
you're not running where before you
could only walk first you walked then
you started power walking and now you're
running
and let me tell you running is good for
the heart
walking is good for the heart yes yes
yes romans 10 says for with the heart
man believes
unto righteousness
so beloved if we're to walk by faith
what god is telling us is the stronger
your heart is the stronger your heart is
the more cardio you do the more fat
you're gonna burn so we burn fat and we
build muscle all at the same time
let me talk about this last thing rest
rest and then we're done i got two
verses one verse
two verses
listen
rest
if you don't get rest
the body grows when you sleep
you may not have known that
that's why bodybuilders are always
trying to sleep
because the body grows when you rest
yeah y'all catching this
the body grows when you
rest
you do know
you do know that jesus
after his workout remember on the cross
what did he do next
he rested
he rested all right whoo
what a workout time to go rest
time to go rest and watch this
after he rested and woke up three days
later watch what the text says
i love this watch what the text says
matthew 28 16 then the eleven disciples
went away into galilee into a mountain
where jesus had appointed them and when
they saw him they worshiped him but some
doubted and jesus came and spake unto
them saying all power is given unto me
in heaven and in earth y'all didn't
catch that
jesus worked out
concentric
eccentric
isometric
he was totally hydrated even though he
said i thirst
he rested
and when he woke up
boom
the goat
the greatest of all time
this is why beloved jesus says come unto
me all you that labor and are heavy
laden and i will give you rest listen to
me stress
creates a catabolic state in the body
you want to be anabolic
jesus says rest in me
rest
in
me
today you're saying lord
i am ready to work out
i have never been more ready to work out
now
than now
i am ready to work out
and i know that seven weeks from now i'm
not gonna be walking around like a like
a superhuman i know that
but if i can get stronger if i can be
stronger seven weeks from now than i was
today i'm happy with that if i can lose
some weight by seven weeks i'm happy
with that i know that i'll have to do
this again and again and again and again
and keep working this out because i'm
working out my salvation with trembling
and fear i know that i have to keep
working out but if i can at least start
if i can be swole in the spirit gg
so we're gonna put the link in the chat
and that's my appeal
my appeal
my call to action
is to do this seven week workout
that's my call to action
lord i need you to train me during this
seven week workout by the way in the
seven week workout we're using the
sanctuary the articles of furniture in
the sanctuary as the basis for
everything you just heard
put that one in the chat if you're
saying lord i want to be in that workout
put that one in the chat
and as many ones in the chat i hope i
see you click that link
to join that seven week workout you can
do it by yourself you can do it with a
group however you want to do it
but do it
put that one in the chat if you're
saying lord that's me
that's me i need to i need to learn how
to train
intelligently
while you're putting that one in the
chat we're just going to pray heavenly
father
i want to thank you lord for speaking
clearly to us today
i want to thank you for the power of
your word i want to thank you lord that
you are able to take the gospel and
against so many different applications
make it practical to us
and so lord today we are praying that
you would train us
to become stronger christians
train us to lose the fat of sin help us
to get our steps in help us to stay
hydrated help us lord to build muscle
help us lord to get stronger help us
lord help
us to rest in you
and lord where many of us are doubting
and struggling and and looking at that
picture in the mirror and saying there's
no hope for me
lord may
may the workout that you are showing us
may these things make that difference
and start us on the path to becoming
strong and fit
for the kingdom of heaven
this we pray in the precious and holy
name of jesus amen
and amen
i want to thank you guys for uh joining
us today we're going to put the alter
live link in the chat
so uh there it is uh for those of you
who know of people that were watching
earlier that got cut off and didn't see
the second link
please just let them know go ahead and
put this in the in the share this so let
others know that they can jump on and um
god bless you
i hope that your hearts have been set on
fire today
um i hope that you're looking forward to
this character transformation program
and um have a blessed sabbath by the way
let me announce uh that this evening uh
tomorrow or some this evening i'm sorry
at 5 00 p.m central standard time i will
be doing a study it will only be on the
power of the lamb channel and that study
is on matthew 24 and the close of
probation
so be aware of that that's coming up at
5 p.m
central standard time it's going to be
an extended study
[Music]
so that's it god bless you and have a
good rest of your sabbath